奥马哈
品质保证
两百年历史
朋友你好*
*Well, hello, there
好久不见*
My, it's been a long, long time
你问我最近如何*
*How am I doin'?
我觉得还凑合*
*Oh, I guess that I'm doin' fine
辛那邦[美国烘焙连锁店]
时光飞逝*
*It's been so long now
你想让镜子里的这个人为你服务吗
感觉却像*
*And it seems that
只是昨日*
*It was only yesterday
时光飞逝*
*Gee, ain't it funny
真是可笑*
*How time slips away
我该走了*
*Gotta go now
改日再见*
*Guess I'll see you around
却不知何时能再见*
*Don't know when, though
不知我何时回到镇上*
*Never know when I'll be back in town
晚安  女士们  路上小心
Good night, ladies. Get home safe.
但请记得*
*But remember
我曾说过*
*What I tell you
总有一天*
*That, in time,
你会付出代价*
*you're gonna pay
时光飞逝*
*And it's surprising
真是惊讶*
*How time slips away
不不不
No, no, no, no!
该死
God damn it!
不  别这样
No! Oh, c-come on.
来人啊
Somebody!
紧急出口
打开这扇门
会触发警报
警方会收到通知
紧急出口
向下扳开门  触发警报
索尔·古德曼到此一游
绝命律师
第二季 第一集
他来了
Ah, here he is.
太棒了
Oh, great.
吉米  真准时  很高兴能见到你
Jimmy, right on time. Good to see you.
-你好  霍华德  -你们好
- Hello, Howard. - Hey. Hi.
这位是詹姆斯·麦吉尔  这位是克利福德·梅因
James McGill, Clifford Main.
叫我吉米就好  幸会  克利福德
Just "Jimmy." And it's a pleasure to meet you, Clifford.
幸会  我们知道你为矶鹞渡一案做出的努力
Likewise. We know all about your work on Sandpiper.
是团队成果
Well, it's a group effort.
哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所的人
I mean, the folks at HHM
做得非常好
are just knocking it out of the park.
如果没有你  也就不会立案
Well, you know, the case wouldn't exist without you.
当然
Absolutely.
一旦他加入你的团队
Once you get him on your team,
就知道我为什么叫他"骗子查理"了
you'll know why I call him "Charlie Hustle."
吉米  他们是我的律师
Jimmy, these are my associates --
布莱恩·阿楚莱塔和艾琳·布里尔
Brian Archuleta and Erin Brill.
-很高兴认识你们  -幸会
- Nice to meet you both. - It's great to meet you.
非常抱歉
I hate to do this,
但我能跟韦克斯勒小姐单独说句话吗
but, um, could I borrow Ms. Wexler for a moment?
失陪一下
If you will excuse us?
失陪
Pardon me.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我
I just, um
听着  是这样
Listen, here's the thing.
如果我接受这份工作  是否意味着我俩...
If I take this job, does that mean the two of us...
我是说...
I mean, uh...
是否意味着...
Does it mean, uh...
什么  你到底想说什么
What? What -- what the hell is this?
如果我今天接受戴维斯梅因律所的工作
If I take this job today, with Davis and Main,
是否意味着你和我...
does that mean that you and me...
能成吗
Is this -- is this gonna happen?
吉米  我...
Jimmy, I...
我...
I...
这两件事没有任何联系
One thing has absolutely nothing to do with the other.
完全无关吗
Nothing at all.
无关
No.
当然无关了  为什么会有呢
Of course not. Why would it?
好吧
Great.
非常抱歉
Oh, sorry about that.
我想说  衷心感谢你们
Listen, I just wanted to say thank you sincerely
考虑我
for your interest in me.
这是我的荣幸
It's a honor to be considered,
但是现在  尤其是现在
but at this time...at this time,
我想我还是不加入了
Um...I'm gonna have to take myself out of the running.
非常感谢
Thanks.
谢谢你  霍华德
Thank you, Howard.
吉米
Jimmy.
挺快啊
That was quick.
不收费
No charge.
帮我想想
Help me out here.
我是在做梦
Did I dream it?
还是我办公桌上真的有一百六十万美元现金
Or did I have 1.6 million dollars on my desk in cash?
地球上没人知道我们有这钱
No one on god's green earth knew we had it.
我们可以五五分成
We could have split it 50/50.
我们本可以每人带八十万美金回家  不用交税
We could have gone home with $800,000 each, tax-free.
你想说什么
Your point being?
我们为什么没那么干
Why didn't we?
我记得你说  要做对的事
I remember you saying something about doing the right thing.
你想知道我为什么没拿那钱吗
You want to know why I didn't take that money?
你是想问这个吗
Is that what you're asking?
没错  我是想问那个问题
Yeah, that's what I'm asking.
对我个人来说  别人雇我干活
Me, personally -- I was hired to do a job.
我干完了  就结束了
I did it. That's as far as it goes.
是的
Yeah.
我知道是什么阻止了我
Well, I know what stopped me.
听好了
You know what?
它再也不会阻止我了
It's never stopping me again.
你们好  女士们
Chao chi c'ung, ladies.
你们好
Chao chi c'ung.
阮女士  外面天气很好
Mrs. Nguyen, it's beautiful day out there.
你偶尔也要出去一下
You should get out of this place once in a while, you know.
扔扔飞盘什么的  散散心
Throw a Frisbee, have some fun.
我要经营生意
I have a business to run.
不  不对
Uh, no.
是生意在"经营"你呢
The business is running you.
听我的
Listen to me.
你以后会感谢我的
You'll thank me later.
只有顾客才能享用黄瓜水
Cucumber water for customer only!
詹姆斯·麦吉尔律所
喂  是我啊
Hey! It's me!
天啊  听得见吗
Geez. Hello?
嘿
Hello?
是我啊  我买了新车
It's me. I got a new car.
你喜欢吗
You like it?
我们不能开这个去碰面
We're not taking that to the meet.
那我们怎么去呢
How are we gonna get there?
我来开车
I'll drive.
开我的车
My car.
为什么
Why?
这桩生意要求克制
This business requires restraint.
但这车恰恰相反
That is the opposite of restraint.
但是我喜欢它
But...I like it.
我是说  我为它自豪
I mean, I'm proud of it.
好的
Good.
那你一个人自豪去  别拉着我
Then you be proud of it on your own time, but not with me.
我拒绝上车
I'm not getting in that.
好吧  那  那就别上车了
Okay. Then -- then don't.
实话说  你也没干什么
Honestly, uh, you don't really do anything.
你只是站在我背后而已
I've been paying you the salary of three people
我就要付你三人份的报酬
to just stand behind me.
而且  而且最近几次交易
You know? And -- and these-- these last few deals --
这个叫纳乔的  他都是一个人来的
This Nacho fella, he's been coming alone.
如果他不需要带人
I mean, if he doesn't need backup men,
那我为什么要带你呢
then, I mean, why do I need you?
我应该一个人去
I should just go alone.
不然我就浪费钱了
I'm throwing -- I'm throwing away money.
跟扔垃圾堆里一样
Just tossing it away. Into the trash.
随你怎么办
Look, you do whatever you want,
但是我建议你  如果没有人跟着你
but I'm advising you -- do not go to that meet
别一个人去
without someone watching your back.
是啊  你当然会这么说了
Yeah, well, of course you're gonna say that.
你才不想失去这份轻松赚大钱的工作
I mean, you don't want to be out of this easy-peasy job.
不过抱歉  这个肥差
Well, I'm sorry, but this is the gravy train,
马上就要溜走了
and it's leaving the station right now.
所以最后一次机会
So last chance.
上车
All aboard.
我说真的  最后一次机会
Seriously, last chance.
我数到十  然后我就...
I'm gonna count to, say, 10, and then I'm...
好  那行
All right, then.
你的服务到此为止了
Your services are no longer needed!
你好
Hola.
老头子没来
No old guy?
怎么  他是扭到腰了还是怎么了
What, did he break a hip or something?
是啊
I know, right?
不过不是的  我们...
Yeah, no, we, uh...
我们散伙了
we -- we parted ways.
产生了一些分歧
Yeah, saw things differently.
所以...  你懂的
So... You know how it is.
这车不错
This is interesting.
是啊  你喜欢吗
Oh, yeah. You like it?
我能看看吗
Can I take a look?
随意参观  请上车
Be my guest. Get in.
进去看看
Check it out.
真不错
Impressive.
谢谢  上车看看  感受下真皮
Thank you. Get in. Feel the leather.
是H2型
Yeah, it's a H2.
新款才下线
Brand-new off the line.
比H1型轻巧但车身稍长  车顶更高
Slimmer than the H1 but longer, more height.
这车相当不错
Yeah, it's a honey.
V8引擎  325马力
V-8 engine, 325 horsepower,
三区空调系统
tri-zone climate controls.
即使坐在车里的姑娘
So you can have a girl in a bikini
一个穿着比基尼而另一个穿着大衣
and another in a parka,
也都会感觉很舒适
and they're both gonna be comfortable.
带着两个姑娘  开着SUV
You're running around with two girls in your S.U.V.,
真是爽翻天了
you'd be really comfortable, huh?
是啊
Oh, yeah. Yes.
我去点下钱
I'm gonna count this quick.
数吧  别数错了
Do your thing. Make sure it's right.
新墨西哥州  机动车辆管理局
车辆登记证书
好了
Okeydokey.
没问题
We are good.
跟以前一样
Uh, same as before.
没开过封的
Uh, still factory-sealed.
跟往常一样  你尽管点一下
And, as always, you're welcome to count them.
我相信你
I trust you.
很好  谢谢
Great. Thank you.
下次见
See you next time.
你好
Hello?
是的
Yes.
不  抱歉
Uh, no. Sorry.
但是...  对  我是詹姆斯·麦吉尔
But -- Yes, this is James McGill,
但我不做律师了  所以...
but I'm no longer a lawyer, so...
对  不做律师了  再见
That's right -- not a lawyer. Bye.
这就是中年危机的表现吗
So, this is what a midlife crisis looks like?
不是中年危机
Not midlife crisis.
是醒悟
Clarity.
中年醒悟
Midlife clarity.
醒悟
Clarity?
那你给我解释清楚为什么要放弃
Clearly explain to me why you walked out
你这辈子最好的工作机会
on the best job opportunity of your life.
进池子里  我就告诉你
Get in the pool, and I'll tell ya.
进池子里
Get in the pool?
对  来啊
Yeah. Come on.
去纪念品商店买件泳衣
Just pop in the gift shop and buy a bathing suit --
连体的就行  不用太花哨
get a one-piece, nothing fancy.
水温正好  二十八度
The water is perfect. It's 82 degrees.
点一杯喝的
You can order a drink.
然后尝尝这的薯片蘸酱
And you got to try this crab dip.
你为什么要这样
Why are you acting like this?
我没怎么样
I'm not acting like anything.
我只是  终于下定决心做我自己
I just... finally decided to be me.
还好吗康普森先生  要再来一杯吗
Everything okay, Mr. Cumpston? Would you like another drink?
不用了
Uh, I'm good with this.
你给我听好  康普森先生
I'll tell you what, Mr. Cumpston.
如果你真想谈谈  我在酒吧等你
If you really want to talk, I'll be in the bar.
我不会等太久
Not for long.
罗兰多
Hey, Rolando.
结账
Check.
"不干法律了"是什么意思
What do -- What do you mean "Quit the law"?
就是不干了  就这么简单
I quit it. Simple as that.
感谢你的解释  吉米
Oh, well, thanks for explaining, Jimmy.
-现在清楚多了  -伙计
- It's super-clear now. - Hey, buddy?
这里是印错了吗
Uh, is that a misprint right there?
一定是印错了
It's got to be, right?
-陈年蓝宝石吗  -是的
- The Zafiro Añejo? - Yeah.
没印错  真的
That's correct, actually, believe it or not.
老天爷  一杯龙舌兰要五十美金吗
Holy shit. A $50 shot of tequila?
-值吗  -当然
- Is it worth it? - Apparently.
不过也看个人喜好了
I mean, it's kind of a personal-choice kind of thing.
这辈子一定得尝尝五十美金的龙舌兰
Well, I can't die without trying a $50 shot of tequila,
两杯  纯的
so, uh...two -- dos -- neat.
能跟房费一起结  对吗
And, uh, we can charge that to the room, can't we?
不  不用  我们
No, we can't. We...
我来付
I am paying.
给他一杯这里最便宜的
And he will be having a shot of your well brand,
我要一杯普通红酒
and I'll have a glass of your house red.
我们有解百纳  比诺和西拉
We have a Cabernet, a Pinot, and a Syrah.
都可以
Whatever. Dealer's choice.
有酒精就行
Something with alcohol.
没问题
You got it.
吉米  在西塞罗市发生了什么
Jimmy... did something happen in Cicero?
为什么西塞罗市一定要有事发生
Why did something have to happen in Cicero?
因为我跟你说起戴维斯梅因律所时
Because when I talked to you about Davis & Main,
你都准备好接受那份工作了
you were ready to take the job.
现在你回来了  突然要放弃法律工作
Now you're back, and you're suddenly quitting the law,
在酒店骗喝昂贵的酒
cheating hotels out of expensive liquor,
带一个奇怪的尾戒
wearing a weird pinkie ring?
怎么  加入黑手党了吗
What, are you in the mafia now?
还问我们有没有未来
Asking if we have a future.
到底怎么回事
I mean, where did that come from?
我不知道  只是
I don't know. I just...
西塞罗跟这没关系
Well, Cicero has nothing to do with it.
是我的人生
It's my whole life.
从查克让我来到阿尔布开克开始
Well, my life since Chuck made me come to Albuquerque.
自从我来到这儿
Ever since I got here,
我所做的一切都是为了让查克高兴
all I've done is try to make Chuck happy,
使出浑身解数来讨好查克
bend over backwards to please Chuck.
查克  查克  查克  再也不这样了
Chuck, Chuck, Chuck. Well, no more.
你放弃从事法律  这不正是查克想要的
You quitting the law -- isn't that exactly what Chuck wants?
谁在乎呢
Who cares?
这是为了我自己  好吗
This is for me, okay?
因为各种错误的原因  我开始从事法律
I-I got into the law for all the wrong reasons.
我相信自己的直觉
I'm trusting my instincts.
我的才华还是发挥在别处比较好
I think that my talents are better spent elsewhere.
在哪儿  漂在别人的泳池里吗
Where? Floating in somebody else's pool?
吉米  你是个了不起的律师
Jimmy, you're a great lawyer.
为什么要放弃
Why give that up?
也不是说我不享受做律师
I'm not saying it didn't have its moments,
只是我所喜欢的事
but the stuff I liked about it --
说服别人  让别人信服
selling people, convincing people --
不当律师也可以做到
I don't have to be a lawyer to do that.
还有  我知道别人怎么看我
Besides, people tell me how they see me,
他们并不把我当律师
and it's not as a lawyer.
这是您要的酒
All right. Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
还需要什么随时叫我
Lemme know if I can get you guys anything else, okay?
波比  怎么样  伙计
Bobby, what up, brother man?
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
做空
Short it.
做空  把那垃圾做空
Short it. Short that shit.
那支股毫无价值  没有前途
That stock is useless. It's got no legs.
就像马戏团的怪咖  但一点都不搞笑
It's like a circus freak minus the fun.
那支更糟糕  谁跟你推荐的
And that one's even worse. Who's giving you these?
帮我一个忙  拿个枕头
Please do me a favor. Take a pillow,
放在那支股票的脸上
put it over that stock's face
直到你听到垂死呻吟
until you hear the deathbed queef.
-是个赔钱货  -好吧
- It's a loser. - Okay, so...
如果你不做律师  要做什么
if you're not gonna be a lawyer, then what?
漂着等矶鹞渡的钱到手吗
Float around and wait for your Sandpiper money to roll in?
-不  -那可能要好几年
- No. - That could take years.
矶鹞渡跟这没关系
Sandpiper has no bearing on this at all.
这个有前途
Yeah, it's got legs.
那好  有什么计划
Okay, then, what's the plan?
用开放的心态迎接未来
To be open to the universe.
那就是没计划
Okay, so no plan.
随心所欲
Just walk the Earth,
像《低俗小说》结尾的朱尔那样吗
like Jules at the end of "Pulp Fiction"?
无论未来给我什么
Look, whatever the universe presents,
无论有什么样的机会  我都会接受
whatever opportunity arises, I will take it.
-无论什么样的机会吗  -是的
- Whatever opportunity? - Yeah.
戴维斯梅因律所不是一个机会吗
Wasn't Davis & Main an opportunity?
是非常好的机遇  但你放弃了
It's a great opportunity, and you're walking away from it.
不是他  不是那个人...
Not him, not the guy who...
拒绝前难道不该至少试一下这份工作吗
Look, shouldn't you at least try the job before you say no?
浪费所有人  包括我自己的时间
And waste everyone's time, including my own?
金  谢谢你的关心  但那不适合我
Kim, I appreciate your concern, but it's not for me.
我不想要
I don't want it.
吉米  你记得你为司法考试学了多久
Jimmy, do you remember how long you studied for that bar?
你有多用功
How hard you worked?
所有努力都付之一炬吗
All that effort, you're just gonna toss it away?
这是沉没成本谬误
That's the Sunk Cost Fallacy.
认为已经花了很多时间  金钱和精力的事就应该继续下去
什么
W-- The what?
沉没成本谬误  是赌徒行为
The Fallacy of Sunk Cost -- it's what gamblers do.
赔了夫人又折兵
They throw good money after bad
以为自己运气好  能回本
thinking they can turn their luck around.
我已经花了这么多钱和时间
It's like, "I've already spent this much money or time --
无论怎样我都得继续
whatever, I got to keep going!"
但游戏最后是没有回报的
No, there's no reward at the end of this game.
你错了
You are making a mistake.
我知道你错了
I know you're making a mistake.
我这些年一直在做所谓正确的事
I've been doing the "right" thing for all these years now,
但我落得什么下场  糟透了
and where has it gotten me? Nowhere.
抱歉  我不...
I'm sorry. I don't...
我没点
It's not my thing.
我不懂
I don't get it.
-我就是不懂  -这才是对的事
- I just don't get it. - It's what's right for me.
扯淡
Donkey balls.
纯粹扯淡  伙计
Pure donkey balls, dude.
华尔街是废柴待的地方
Wall Street's for suckers.
谁吃饱了撑的想去那儿啊
Who needs that aggravation?
如果股神巴菲特不非得待在那儿
If the the Oracle doesn't have to live there,
那我肯定不去
then I sure as hell don't.
我坐马桶上  用手提电脑就能交易
I can make a million-dollar stock trade on my laptop
一百万美元的股票
sitting on a toilet.
就像麦德斯往我王座上拉金砖
Like Midas, shitting gold bricks on my throne.
麦德斯  传说能点石成金的人
所以斯皮尔格曼和戴伊奇才这么想要我的生意
That's why Speigelman and Deitch want my business so bad.
我是大金主
I'm a golden God.
我当然记得  谁会忘记那种事
Look, of course I remember that. Who forgets a thing like that?
那种屁话是被压抑弱势群体的愤怒
That fart had the anger of a repressed minority community.
你当着谁的面放这种屁
You fart like that in someone's face,
他下辈子准得红眼病
you're gonna give them pinkeye for life.
聊得很愉快  伙计
Good convo, bro.
下次再说  兄弟
Till next time, brutha-man.
跟我来
Come with me.
-什么  -来就好  相信我
- What? - Just come on. Trust me.
你要干什么
What are you gonna do?
你想明白我说的话
You want to understand what I'm talking about?
就跟我来
Follow my lead.
伙计  能帮我们解决一个赌局吗
Hey, buddy, could you settle a bet for us?
-我怎么  -抱歉
- I what? - Uh, sorry.
我并不想搞得像我在偷听
I don't want to make it sound like I was eavesdropping,
但我不小心听到了
but I kind of was.
我们听到你说股票的事
Uh, we heard you talking about stocks.
那么问题来了
Yeah, so, question --
你能不能解决我和我妹妹的争论
if you could settle a debate between me and my sister.
算了吧  我们不该打扰这位...
Uh, you know what? We probably shouldn't be bothering this --
我们一般不麻烦别人  是吧
We wouldn't normally do this -- right?
但我们需要一个专家
But we need an expert.
他听起来好像很懂行
This guy sounds like he knows his stuff.
没错  你说
Yeah, go.
行  问题是这样的
Okay. Here's the question.
在股票市场中
Uh, when it comes to the stock market,
允许个人投资的金额
is there, like, a financial limit
有没有限制
to how much a person's allowed to invest?
限制
A limit?
没  没限制
No. No limit.
我就知道  那如果是遗产呢
Knew it. Oh, even if it's an inheritance?
比如  要交遗产税之类的
You know, with, like, inheritance taxes and whatnot?
同样没有
Nope. Same.
太棒了  谢谢  伙计
That's -- oh, fantastic. Thank you, buddy.
听到没  没限制  跟你说了我们能全投进去
See? No limit. Told you we could invest it all.
而且这也是明智之举
And it's a smart move, too.
全存银行里  不行
Sticking it all in the bank? No.
没错  你可以投资所有的钱
Yeah. You can... invest all your money.
但确保要分散投资
Just make sure you diversify.
没错  分散投资
Yeah. Diversify.
那...  你得...
That's -- You got to --
你说的"分散投资"是什么意思
Oh, hey, um... what do you mean, "diversify"?
分散投资就是
Well, diversify is --
你听过一句名言
Y-you know that saying,
"鸡蛋别全放在一个篮子里"  是吧
"Don't put all your eggs in one basket," right?
一个道理
Same principle.
没错  有道理  谢谢
No, it makes complete sense. Thank you.
如果你能告诉你要投多少钱
Now, if I had an idea of the money we're talking about --
大致数目  我可以教你精明地分散投资
ballpark -- I could give you examples of smart diversification.
好吧...
Yeah, um...
听着  我们父亲那边的一位叔叔最近去世了
Look, an uncle on our father's side recently passed,
给我们留下了大约一百四十万的遗产
and he left us somewhere in the neighborhood of $1.4 million.
不是我这人贪心  但我觉得
And I don't mean to be greedy, but I think,
如果我们现在明智地投资
if we invest it smart now,
我们可以将它翻两倍  三倍
we could double it, triple it --
甚至可以将这笔钱翻四倍  对吗
we could quadruple the whole inheritance, right?
在我看来
In my opinion?
财富属于有胆量的人  兄弟
Fortune favors the bold, man.
如果你们有时间和我喝一杯
Now, if you guys are free to join me for a drink,
我可以给你们简单参谋一下
I can give you a quick consult.
没关系  我们自己能行
That's all right. We were gonna do it ourselves
用那种在线经纪网站就行
through one of those online brokerage websites.
我们打算选个经典点的  比如...
We're just gonna pick, uh, a classic, like --
好像是叫蓝筹股
I think they're called blue-chip stocks?
对  对  你们自己完全没问题
Yeah, yeah, yeah, you can totally do it yourself.
就挑那些可靠的
Shoot for the tried and true.
当然  你们可能会把钱投到兴登堡号
'Course, you might be putting your cash in the Hindenburg,
德国大型飞艇  运营后第二年烧毁
意大利游轮  1956年与另一船只相撞沉没
安德烈亚·多里亚号
the Andrea Doria,
美国电影  上映后票房惨败
或者  《联邦大蠢探》上
uh..."Corky Romano."
不是吗
Right?
它们当时看起来都可靠极了  可结果呢
They all seemed rock-solid beforehand, but then...
是啊  不怎么好
Yeah, not good.
不怎么好  没错
Not good, yeah.
那要如何区分呢
So, how do you know?
那就需要我们这种人出场了
Well, that's where someone like myself comes in.
资深的理财经理
Proven track record as a wealth manager.
我能规避风险  又敢于冒险
I take calculated but aggressive risks
因为我想抓住转瞬即逝的机遇
'cause I want to catch lightning.
而我确实能
And I do.
我就是一台印钞机
Practically a money-printing machine.
听上去不错
That sounds good.
印钞机
A money-printing machine.
听着  那边有个小隔间
Listen, there's a little booth over here.
方便说话  我们可以谈谈  不用承诺什么
There's some privacy. We can talk. No obligations.
我们可以...  随便谈谈这件事
We can just -- just rap about this a little bit.
-好啊  也可以  -好吗
- Yeah, I guess. - Yeah?
你说呢  妹妹
What do you say, sis?
我们能谈谈吗
Can we just talk?
滑步舞啊
Electric slide on in there.
我们就简单谈两句  不是...
And we'll just rap a little bit. It's no --
顺便说一句  我叫肯
My name's Ken, by the way.
维克多  中间是"K"
Uh, Viktor, with a "K."
好啊  中间是"K"的维克多
Cool. Viktor with a "K."
这位迷人的女士呢
And this lovely lady is?
我叫...吉赛尔  吉赛尔·圣·克莱尔
It's...Giselle. Giselle Saint Claire.
好名字
Ah, lovely.
请坐  我不会咬人的
Please, sit. I won't bite.
那么  中间是"K"的维克多和吉赛尔
So, Viktor with a "K" and Giselle
异域风情的名字
exotic names.
是荷兰人名
They're Dutch.
准确地说  是布尔人
Well, Boer, to be precise.
我们父亲家那边来自南非
Our...father's side of the family is from South Africa,
汉弗莱叔叔就是在那去世的
which is where Uncle Humphrey passed away.
南非
South Africa.
那里盛产美女啊  不是吗
They grow them beautiful down there, right?
查理兹·塞隆  还有你
Charlize Theron. And you.
我其实没在那待过  不过希望以后能去
I've never actually been, but hope to go someday.
听着  等我为你们理财结束
Tell you what, by the time I'm done with you two,
你们可能连私人飞机都有了
you might be taking your own private jet.
好极了
Nice.
不好意思  我们都坐这儿了
Excuse me. Hi. Uh, we are sitting here now,
所以我们需要一份酒单  如果你...
so, uh, we could use a wine list, if you get a chance --
你喜欢喝龙舌兰吗
Hey, uh, are a tequila fan?
喜欢
Yes.
你想喝吗
You down for that?
你喝过陈年蓝宝石吗
You ever try Zafira Añejo?
没喝过  不过我喝什么都行
No, I have not, but I'm down for whatever.
来三杯她说的那个
Three of whatever she just said.
-没问题  -好的
- You got it. - All right.
那么  股票市场  很棒的投资途径
So, stock market. A great investment.
现在正是入市的好时机
And you're picking the right time to jump in.
你为什么要听我的  我是个白痴
Why do you listen to me? I'm an idiot.
谈论他的豪车  谈论...
And talks about his cars, talks about --
-他有多少辆车  -我觉得...
- How many cars did he have? - I don't think --
-那没道理啊  -没错  肯
- It doesn't make sense. - That's it, Ken.
这是酒保送给你们的
Compliments of the bartender.
她觉得你们可能想留个纪念
She thought you might want a souvenir.
天啊  我们把整瓶酒喝光了吗
Oh, my God. Did we drink the entire bottle?
还没呢
Not yet, we didn't.
-来  -干杯
- Boom. - Hey, cheers.
我觉得我们该结账了
Uh, I think we're ready for the check.
不  这是最明智的方式
No, really, it's the smart way to go.
好吧  不过说清楚
Okay. But, so, to be clear,
你直接从我们的账户取钱来投资
you take the money directly from our account and invest it.
-分散投资  -分散投资
- Diversify. - Diversify it.
接着所有红利和利润
And then all the dividends and all the profits
还有...我们给你的钱都会回到我们的账户
and the...what-have-you comes back into our account.
没错  说得太对了
Boom. Absolutely.
你们还会拿到一份详细说明
And you'll get a detailed statement
上面写着你们的钱涨了多少
showing you how much your money is growing --
当月最牛的股票等等
biggest bulls of the month, et cetera.
肯  兄弟  就这么办吧
Ken, buddy... let's do this.
好  签在这儿  中间是"K"的维克多
Great. Right there, Viktor with a "K,"
吉赛尔  等下你也签
and, Giselle, you are next.
好刺激啊
This is so exciting.
很高兴能为你们服务
Folks, it's been a pleasure.
-我来买单  -我可不会让你买单
- Oops, I got that. - Can't let you do it, son.
等等  什么  肯  你人真好
Wait. What? Ken, you are the greatest.
-谢啦  -小事一桩
- Thank you. - No problem-o.
听着  这会是你们做的最棒的决定
Hey, this will be the best decision you'll ever make.
我也觉得
Oh, I believe it.
好了  我们就不继续打扰你了
All right, well, we should get out of your hair.
-没错  -等等  别急
- Yeah. - Oh, wait, wait.
这...是给你们的
This...is for you.
上面有我所有的联系方式
Now, that's got all my contact info.
有问题或者有事都可以打给我
Call me anytime with questions or anything at all.
肯
Ken.
再见  记得打给我
Bye. Call me, guys.
-再见  -快来拦着我们啊
- Bye. - Try and stop us.
棒
Wow.
太棒了
Just wow.
我...
What I--
这账没错吧
Is this right?
没错  先生
Yes, sir, it is.
快走快走
Go, go, go, go, go!
陈年蓝宝石
Zafira Añejo!
他会追出来的
He's gonna come out.
不
Oh, no.
我都没看清楚合同
I didn't read the fine print.
-等等  -爽
- Wait. - Yeah!
天呐
Holy crap.
真不敢相信...
I can't b--
你刷完能借我刷吗
Can I borrow that when you're done?
不行  太恶心了
No, that's gross.
怎么会恶心
H-how is it gross?
我们身上的病菌早就混到一起了
Our germs have already intermingled.
这是我的牙刷  情况不一样
It's my toothbrush. It's different.
怎么不一样了
Why is it different?
就是不一样
Because.
牙龈经常出血  就会有...
You know, gums bleed, and there's --
会有唇疱疹病菌  各种食物以及古怪的...
there's cold sores, all sorts of food and weir--
让我看看  来嘛
Let me see that. Come on.
什么  不
What? No!
来嘛  我现在就刷
Come on! I'll do it right now.
-我才不管  -我得刷牙了
- I don't care. - I need to brush my teeth.
我没其它牙刷了  怨不得我
I don't have an extra. It's not my problem.
没关系  我用这个
That's fine. I got this.
很好  这样我不介意
Good. I'm fine with this.
我也不介意
Yeah, me too.
看我等会儿用什么当牙线
Wait till you see what I floss with.
该好好留着这个
That's a keeper.
谢啦  中间是"K"的维克多
Thank you, Viktor with a "K."
如果我们每晚都那样  不是很好吗
Wouldn't it be great if we could do that every night?
是啊  是很好
Yes, it would.
可惜...
But...
我们不能那样
we can't.
我知道
I know, yeah.
只是说说嘛  如果可以  一定会很棒
But I'm just saying, if we could, it would be great.
但我知道我们不能
But I know we can't.
糟了  今天我不能迟到
Oh, crap. I can't be late today.
霍华德要分配任务
Howard is doling out assignments,
最后进门的人
and the last one through the door
只能去复审文件
could get stuck in doc review.
你要出去吗
You got somewhere to go?
是啊  我要去一个地方
Yeah. Uh, yeah, I got somewhere.
好了吗
You good?
好了
Yeah. All good.
你是丹尼尔·沃莫尔德吗
Daniel Wormald?
我是贝克警官  这位是萨克斯顿警官
I'm Officer Baker. This is Officer Saxton.
好的  请进吧
Yeah, please. Come on in.
进来吧  在这里
Come in. It's over here.
看看他们做了什么
See what they did?
全都被盗走了
I mean, all gone.
一个不剩啊  就...
All of them, just --
什么一个不剩
Uh, what's all gone?
我有  我之前有一套棒球卡片的珍藏
I have -- I had a baseball-card collection --
一整套呢...全被盗走了
a major collection -- all stolen.
很遗憾听到这消息
Oh, sorry to hear that.
有很多人知道你收集棒球卡吗
Uh, was it common knowledge that you have baseball cards?
不  也不算多
No, not really.
所以  没什么人格外觊觎你的卡片
So, nobody in particular you can think of wanting them?
没有  我想不出来  没有
No. Not that I -- No.
他们怎么进来的
How'd they get in?
那边的后门
Uh, the back door over here.
我回家吃午饭的时候发现它开着
It was open when I came home for lunch.
本来是锁上的
I mean, it was locked,
他们肯定是撬了锁还怎么的
but they must have jimmied it open or something.
你觉得大概是什么时候的事
At what time, uh, you figure this happened?
我8点15分去上班  12点半回家吃午饭
I left for work at 8:15, came home for lunch at 12:30,
然后立马就报警了
and called you immediately.
有没有丢失其他物品
Was anything else taken?
现金  不少现金
Cash -- a fair bit. Uh, um...
有多少
How much cash?
我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
先关注最重要的东西好吗
You know, let's focus on what's important here, you know?
我只关心我的棒球卡
All I really care about are my baseball cards.
我有一张托普斯家的米奇·曼托新秀卡
You know, I have a Topps Mickey Mantle rookie card
那是独一无二的
that's irreplaceable.
铸币级的
It's a mint,
定位比例正面为60/40  反面为90/10
60/40, 90/10 on the reverse.
我可以列举出很多特色
I can go on.
我所有的卡片都是小心存储的
All my cards are in top-loaders,
如果把它们拿出来风吹日晒的
but if they're taken out and exposed to the elements,
或者是弯折了  天呐可千万别
I mean, or creased, God forbid,
短短几秒钟  就会贬值一大截
I mean, you're looking at a 9-point downgrade in a matter of seconds.
我知道像这样的案子
I understand the first 48 hours
案发后四十八小时是破案的黄金时期
are the most important in investigations like this,
时间过去越久
so the more time passes,
找到失物的可能性就越小
I mean, the less likely we are of a recovery.
所以  时间宝贵啊  兄弟们
So...time is of the essence here, guys.
我们会尽全力帮助你的  沃莫尔德先生
Well, we're gonna help you out the best we can, Mr. Wormald.
很好
Good.
他们还真是把这地方翻了个底朝天
They really tossed this place.
你确定他们不是在找其他东西吗
I mean, are you sure they weren't looking for anything else?
比如说
Like what?
我不知道  只是问问你的想法
I don't know. J-Just wondering your thoughts.
我猜他们想找更多棒球卡吧
I assume more baseball cards.
除了锁在那个盒子里的
Did you have more baseball cards
你还有其他棒球卡吗
than the ones you keep locked in that case here?
有  在后面  好几千张呢
Yes, in -- in back -- thousands.
但是这些才是极品
But these were the crown jewels over here.
全明星阵容
You know, t-the all-star lineup.
好吧
Right.
怎么了
What?
我只是想理清一下状况
Just trying to make sense of it.
有什么好理的
What's to make sense of?
不就是小偷来偷棒球卡吗  多简单
I mean, isn't it as simple as the perp was looking for more baseball cards?
或者是嗑药嗑嗨了
Or hopped up on speed or whatever
疯了一样来这扫荡一通
and went nuts with the vandalism?
是啊  也有可能
Yeah. I mean, that could be.
外面那辆悍马挺酷的
Pretty sweet Hummer parked in the driveway.
是你的吗
That yours?
对  是我的
Yeah, that's mine.
租来的
Uh, it's a lease.
价钱特别划算
Got a great deal on it.
真酷
It's very sweet.
你知道吗  他们说悍马
You know, they say Arnold Schwarzenegger
就是为了阿诺德·斯瓦辛格而生的
is the reason that Hummers exist.
我也不知道为什么  他们就这么说的
I don't know how, but that's what they say.
真的啊
No kidding.
你是做什么工作的  沃莫尔德先生
What kind of work do you do, Mr. Wormald?
我是搞IT的
Uh, I work I.T.,
在一家制药公司上班
uh, for a pharmaceutical company.
哇  捣鼓电脑的
Wow. Computers.
天哪  我就该学计算机的
God, I should've gotten into computers.
-那我也能开那样的悍马了  -没错
- I'd have that same Hummer. - Yeah, right.
兄弟们  我很高兴你们喜欢我的车
Look, guys, I'm glad you like my car,
但我觉得我们现在
but I think we're looking through
重点错了吧
the wrong end of the telescope here.
最重要的是要找到我的棒球卡
You know, the priority is my baseball cards.
当然
Of course.
好的  我把我的所有藏品列了一份详细清单
Yes, now, I have a detailed manifest of my entire collection
高价的卡片旁边标了星号
and asterisks next to the high-ticket items,
所以很容易就能看出来他们会最先出手哪些
so it's clear which ones they're gonna try to fence first,
因为这些超级超级值钱
'cause they're super, super valuable.
你们需要拿着这份清单去找典当行
So you're gonna want to get this list out to pawnshops,
收藏爱好者  查问所有
uh, collectors, question anyone who's done
有类似前科的人
any sort of crime like this in the past.
那些按常理来说有嫌疑的人
You know, the -- the usual suspects.
我能把名单给你们  好让你们开始调查吗
Uh, can I get you the list so you can start investigating?
好的  那样再好不过了
Yeah, you -- Yeah, if you could get us that list...
我会...我会打印出来的
Okay, I'll -- I'll print it out.
汉克·阿伦卡  铸币级
Hank Aaron, mint.
天  我的德瑞克·基特签名
God, my signed Derek Jeter.
威利·梅斯  奥皮奇收藏卡
Willie Mays, O-Pee-Chee.
深呼吸  深呼吸
Got to breathe. Just keep breathing.
继续深呼吸
Keep breathing.
-真奇怪  -就是说啊
- Okay. - I know, right?
没拿走电视机
Left the TV.
-没拿走电脑  -没错
- Left the computer. - Right.
眼前这情况看上去有点不对劲
There's something wrong with this picture.
喂  是我
Hey, it's me.
我又在这个天堂度过了完美的一天
Another perfect day in paradise out here.
我在泳池里
I'm in the pool.
给我回电
Okay, call me.
-你好吗  -宝贝  吃过中饭了吗
- How are you? - Hey, babe. Did you get lunch?
我吃了
I did.
我觉得我背上快被晒焦了
You know, I think I'm burning up back here.
真的吗  你可真走运
Oh, really? Well, you're just in luck.
-瞧瞧我拿了什么  -太好了
- Look what I have. - Oh, hey, great.
你这里都被晒红了
Oh, yeah, you're all red back here. Yeah.
好爽啊  宝贝
That feels good, babe.
我跟你说了不要在太阳下待太久
I told you not to spend so much time in the sun.
你就是不听
You don't listen.
喂  又是我
Yeah, it's me again.
我说话这当儿  离我不到八米的地方
Listen, as I speak, not 25 feet away from me,
我正看着目标
I'm looking at the mark.
喜剧《盖里尔的岛》中的大富翁
想象下豪威尔·瑟斯顿三世和金吉同居后的样子
Think Thurston Howell III if he shacked up with Ginger.
他浑身上下都是古驰牌的
He's dripping in Gucci.
就好像  我蹲在水坑里
It's like I'm at the watering hole,
我是准备出击的母狮  看着那头
and I'm watching the fattest, slowest water buffalo
最肥最迟缓的水牛向我露出了脖子
expose his neck to me, and I'm the lioness ready to strike.
来吧  金
Come, Kim.
加入我吧  加入狮群吧
Join me. Join the pride.
我刚说母狮
Um, I said "Lioness"
是因为狩猎是母狮的活儿
because it's the females who do all the hunting.
只是想准确描述这个物种
Uh, just wanted to be species-accurate,
跟我的性别无关
irrespective of my own sex.
就像《国家地理》那样...
It's a National Geographic thing. Anyway...
快过来
Get out here.
再见
Bye.
圣达菲  新墨西哥州
Santa Fe, New Mexico.
我想知道戴维斯梅因律所的电话
I need the number of a law firm -- Davis & Main.
好的  帮我转接下
Yeah, you can connect me.
公司用车上有多种选择
There are a few options on the company cars.
您有空的时候我们可以安排试驾
We can arrange a test-drive whenever you'd like.
公司用车  哇
Company car -- wow.
不管您在哪儿  都能够
And there's a service that will deliver it right to you,
随叫随到
wherever you want.
如果您觉得不满意
And if you find you're not happy with it,
随时都能换
it's not a big deal to change it out.
听上去真是...
That sounds really, uh...
太好了
Yeah.
这画有意思
This is, uh, interesting.
如果...
Oh, if, uh...
如果这不符合您的品味
If this isn't to your taste,
我们仓库里有各种画作
we have a collection of art in-house
您可自由选择
you can, uh, choose from.
只要您有空
Anytime you're ready,
我能给您一些样品供您挑选
I can put together some samples for you to review.
我...不  我就喜欢这个
I-I-I -- No, I like this.
好的  您要是还有别的需要  我随时效劳
Good. Uh, well, any other needs you have, I'm here to help.
办公用品  饮食需求...
Office supplies, dietary needs...
有什么指定的食物想放在冰箱里吗
Anything special you want stocked in the fridge?
要加湿器吗  这里有点干燥
Uh, maybe a humidifier? Gets kind of dry in here.
奥马尔  我这人很随意的
Omar, I-I'm pretty low-maintenance.
好的  如果您有任何需求
Sure. Well, if there's anything you need,
我就在外面
I'm right outside the door.
好
Great.
要是我想起什么的话
If I think of anything.
好
Good.
对了  你觉得...
Hey, do you think, um...
我只是在看这张桌子
I'm just looking at this.
我们有其他办公桌可以选吗
D-do we get a choice of desks?
您想要怎样的
What were you thinking?
能不能...
Is it possible, um...
能用...黄檀木的吗
Can we do...cocobolo?
黄檀木办公桌  没问题
Cocobolo desk? Absolutely.
我马上去办
I'll get right on that.
一直开着
不要关